I'm in Hell
Hey there.
（ゼツ）やあ。
How are you doing?
ご機嫌いかが？
（オビト）いいわけ　ねえだろ。
Bad… What do you think?
ここへ来て　どのくらい経つんだ？
How long have I been here?
It feels like it's been a while.
もうずいぶんいる気がする。
家賃いらないから　心配ないよ。
Don't worry,
you don't need to pay rent.
Those of us created from
the Gedo Statue don't have to eat either.
魔像から作られた僕らは
食事しなくてもいいしね。
食費もなし　トイレもなし
うんこもしないし。
No food bills,
no need for a bathroom.
We don't even poo!
だからって
お前らと俺を一緒にするなよ。
Don't lump me in with you guys!
I just have half of that weird stuff
stuck onto me.
俺は半分　その訳わかんないのが
くっついてるだけだ。
And thanks to that, you can survive
without eating or drinking.
そのおかげで　キミも飲まず食わずで
生きてられるんだよ。
In fact, you should be grateful
and thank us.
逆に　ありがとうって
感謝してほしいくらいだよ。
Good grief. We're the ones who don't want
to be lumped in with you!
まったく　こっちこそ
一緒にされたくないね。
What you have is
emotionless synth-tissue.
キミのは感情のない人造体。
We are full artificial humans.
We have feelings and everything!
僕らは人造人間。
ちゃんと感情がある。
それも　ちゃんと笑いのわかる
キミよりいいのがね。
You may have a better sense of humor,
but what we have is much better!
Both our vocabulary skills and mental acuity
are far higher than yours!
ボキャブラリーも頭のキレも
キミより上っすよ。
うんこはしないけど。
But we don't poo…
うるせぇ！
Shut up!
All right, explain how you're at
a higher level than I am!
なら　お前らが俺よりレベル上だって
説明してみろよ。
僕らが。
キミを。
We are…
The ones…
– in charge of watching you!
（２人）見張ってる。
Don't talk in synch!
That pisses me off!
声揃えてんじゃねえ！　むかつく！
リハビリを手伝ってるのは→
We're only helping you
with your rehab
マダラが起きるまでに
キミを回復させて→
because Madara ordered us
to get you up and running
and usable by the time he wakes up.
使えるようにって
命令されてるからだし。
ケッ！　こんな口先だけの
デク人形どもに見張らせて→
So he makes these noisy puppets
keep an eye on me…
while he gets to sleep
the whole time?
自分はずっとおねむかよ。
ぜってぇ　こんなとこ抜け出して
リンとカカシに会うんだ。
I swear I'm gonna get outta here
and return to Rin and Kakashi!
どこから出られる？
Where's the exit?
無理無理！　出口ないよ。
Can't be done…there's no exit.
Madara sealed it off
with a huge boulder…
マダラの命令で
キミをここへ運んだあと→
after we lugged you here
on his orders.
でっかい岩でフタされちゃったから。
What?! He sealed us in?!
（オビト）おい！　塞いだのかよ！
そもそも　前からずっと
リンリンリン　寝言いってますけど→
By the way, you've been saying
"Rin-Rin-Rin" in your sleep a lot.
Do you want to go outside to
collect a bell or something?
外に鈴でも
拾いにいきたいんすか？
Once in a while,
you said "stupid-stupid-stupid.”
たまに　バカバカ　バカバカ！　って。
あっ　バカカシとも言うよね？
And "stupid Kakashi."
Yeah, yeah, that's right!
Every so often.
ああ　そうそう　たま～にね。
バカカシって何？
さあ　直接聞いてみたら？
What's a "stupid Kakashi"?
Beats me. Why don't you ask him?
《んなこと言ってんのか　俺…》
Was I really saying that?
（２人）ヒソヒソ　ヒソヒソヒソ…。
あの　ちょっと質問いいですか？
（オビト）あっ！？
Um, may we ask you a question!
What?
便意…　つまり
うんこをしたくなる気持って→
When nature calls…
In short, what does the urge
to poo feel like?
どんな感じ？　たとえて。
For example…
バカカシじゃねえのかよ！？
I thought you wanted to know
about stupid Kakashi!
Why are you guys so obsessed
with poop?
うんこに　どんだけ興味あんだ
お前ら！
You don't have to get so angry.
何もそんなに怒んなくても。
All right, we'll ask you about
Rin and stupid Kakashi later.
じゃあ
あとでリンとバカカシについて聞くよ。
特にそっちのグルグル！
Especially you, with the swirly face…
うんこしねえくせに
うんこみてぇなヤツな。
You don't poop,
but you look like poop.
お前は嫌！
I hate you!
それより　他の白いのどこ行った？
Anyway, where'd the other white guys go?
They went outside to collect intel.
えっと　外行って情報収集。
What?! You guys can get out?
えっ！？
外へ出られんのかよ？　お前ら。
僕ら
地面の中を移動できるからね。
We can all move through
the earth's surface.
はぁ…　なんだよ　それ。
What the hell?!
俺はこんなとこに閉じ込められ
訳わかんねえ話をされ…。
I'm locked up in here,
and I have to hear about all
this weird stuff.
うんこの話して　すんませんっす！
So sorry to have bothered you
about poo!
その話じゃねえよ！
That's not what I meant!
マダラの話したほう。
I mean, what Madara talked about!
インガを切るだのなんだのと…。
Something about severing fate
and all…
ああ　ガキに合わせて話すほど
人間できてないから。　マダラ。
Oh, that…
Madara's not nice enough to talk
to a brat at his level.
まあ　簡単に言うとね→
Simply put, he's talking
about discarding
本当の世の中の　イヤなことを捨て→
all the bad things in the real world and
いいことだらけの夢の中に
逃げちゃおうって話。
escaping inside a dream
that's full of good things!
夢の中？
夢だから→
Inside a dream?
Since it's a dream,
everything is how you want it!
なんだって思いどおり。
死んだ人だって
生きてることにできる。
Even those who are dead
can be alive again!
ん　ああ…　幻術で
で～っかい夢の世界つくって→
Yeah…
Just think of it as all of us going
to this huge dream world
that was created using genjutsu!
そこに　みんなで行こうってこと。
行こうっていうよりは　無理やり
連れてく感じなんだけど。
Well, it's more like forcibly
taking everyone there…
しかも　一生ね。
and for life too.
幻術で？
With genjutsu?
はぁ…　今度はバカバカしすぎて
意味わかんねえよ！
That's so beyond stupid,
I can't even understand it.
マダラくらい力があれば
なんだってできるよ。
If you have as much power as Madara,
anything is possible.
ただ　今は　弱っててできないよ。
It's just that he's weak right now
and can't do it yet.
だから
いろいろと準備があんのさ。
Much still needs to be prepared.
あっそう。
Oh really? Well, I'm not interested.
興味ねえな。
ん～なことより
俺は　ぜってぇ外へ出るからな！
More importantly…
I swear I'm gonna make it outside!
リンとカカシのもとに。
And get back to Rin and Kakashi!
なに？
この体　使えるようにしねえと。
What?
I've got to get this body working again…
んっ　ああ！
ばんざ～い！
Yaaaay!
ハハハ！
げっ！
なっ！？
What?!
((強がって傷を隠してもダメ。
Don't act tough and hide your wounds!
(ちゃんと見てんだから))
I'm always watching, you know.
《なじんできてる。
It's starting to feel natural.
もう少し…　もう少しで会えるぞ
リン　カカシ》
Just a bit longer.
I'll see you soon, Rin… Kakashi!
さっき　外行ってたんだけど→
I was just outside!
キミの言ってた　リンとバカカシってのが
やばいよ。
Your friends, Rin and
stupid Kakashi, are in trouble!
何があった？
What happened?!
２人きりで　霧隠れの忍たちに
囲まれてる。
They're alone and completely
surrounded by Hidden Mist Shinobi!
うっ　ああ…。
く…。
まだ　その体じゃ
岩は壊せやしないよ。
You can't break through boulders
with that body yet.
リンと　カカシを助けに行かなきゃ。
I have to save Rin and Kakashi…
僕の体を着るといいよ。
Why don't you wear my body?
お前ら　マダラの部下だろ。
いいのか？
But you guys serve Madara.
Are you sure about this?
その子は　いい子だ。
He's…a good boy.
（ゼツ）リンとカカシを
助けたいんでしょ？
Don't you want to help
Rin and Kakashi?
ありがとう　お前ら。
Thanks, you guys!
根をつなげたまま
魔像の力を借りたのね。
You kept the root tethered and
borrowed the statue's power eh? Nice.
やるじゃん。
I'm pretty good, huh?
（ゼツ）僕って　やるもんでしょ。
よし！
All right!
（マダラ）行くか。
So you're going?
助けてくれたことには感謝する。
I'm grateful that you saved me.
But I'm leaving. I have to go.
けど　俺は行く
行かなきゃならねえから。
お前は焦りすぎる。
You're being too hasty…
It may be premature to thank me.
感謝は　まだ早いかもしれんぞ。
たぶん　ここへは二度と来ねえ。
I'll probably never come back here.
一応　礼は言った。　もう行く。
I've given my thanks.
I'm going!
お前は　ここへ帰ってくる。
You…will return.
そのときこそ
本当の礼をもらおう。
And that's when I'll get
your true gratitude.
白いの！
リンとカカシの場所はどこだ？
White one!
What's Rin and Kakashi's location?!
今すぐ案内してくれ。
Take me there right away!
キミの体についたのは
いわば　僕の分身。
What you've got on your body
is like a clone of me.
僕らは　ある程度の距離なら
テレパシーで会話できるし→
And we can talk telepathically to
each other over limited distances.
他の分身体も
あちこちの地下に点在してて→
Others of us are scattered
here and there underground.
情報をやり取りしてる。
We're able to exchange intel.
それを使って　キミを誘導するよ。
グルグル…。
I'll use them to guide you.
Swirly!
First, we need to get outside.
まずは外へ。
頼む。
I'm counting on you.
今のリンとカカシの状況は？
How are Rin and Kakashi
doing right now?
仲間からの情報だと
かなり　やばいみたいだよ。
According to the others,
it looks pretty bad.
霧隠れの実験体が
どうこうとか言ってるけど→
They're talking about some
Hidden Mist test subjects,
but I don't really understand.
僕は　よくわかんない。
実験体？
Test subjects?
とにかく　リンもカカシも
数十人に囲まれてるみたい。
Anyway, it seems Rin and Kakashi
are totally surrounded.
それも　みんな凄腕の上忍や
暗部みたいのばっかだって。
And they're saying they all appear
to be jonin or Black Ops.
ミナト先生は何してる？
誰？
What's Minato Sensei doing?
Who is that?
黄色い閃光は何してる
って聞いてんだ。
I'm asking you what the Yellow Flash
of the Leaf is doing!
う～ん…
何か別の任務中みたいだね。
Seems he's on a different mission.
こんなときに…。
At a time like this?!
((カカシ　リンを頼むぜ。
Kakashi… Look after Rin for me.
(（カカシ）あぁ))
I will.
《オビト：カカシ　お前は約束してくれた。
Kakashi! You made me a promise!
リンを…。
Please…
リンをなんとか守ってくれ！》
Please protect Rin somehow!
俺も　もうすぐ駆けつける。
I'll be right there!
オビト　たぶん　これから戦闘になる。
Obito, this will probably turn
into a battle.
その前に少し
言っときたいんだけど。
So I want to tell you
some things beforehand.
What is it?!
何だ？
キミの戦闘能力は僕より低い。
Your fighting ability is lower
than mine.
更に今は
キミの傷ついた小さな体に→
Plus right now, it's like my big body
is wrapped around
大きな僕の体が覆って
保護してるって感じだから…。
and protecting
your wounded little body.
だから何だよ！？
So what?!
戦闘は僕が動いたほうが
いいと思うけど。
I think it would be better
if I do all the fighting.
マダラも言ってただろ。
Remember what Madara said?
写輪眼は　左右揃って
本来の力を発揮するって。
That only with a pair together
can the Sharingan's true power
be unleashed!
戦場には
俺と対になる写輪眼のカカシがいる。
Kakashi, the other half of my pair,
will be on the battlefield.
ヤツとのコンビネーションは　俺のが上だ！
Our combo attacks are superior!
俺とカカシで　リンを守る！
Kakashi and I will protect Rin!
確かにキミには
柱間の人造体がくっついてる。
As I recall, you do have
Hashirama's tissue attached to you.
千手とうちは
両方の力が合わされば→
A whole different strength may emerge
when Senju and Uchiha powers
are combined together, but…
今までとは違う強さが
あらわれるかもしれないけど…。
何だ？
What was that?
雨かと思ったら　あれか。
I thought it was rain, but it's…
仲間から連絡あり。
I just got w
どうやら　あそこみたいだね。
行くぞ！
《何だ　これ。
変なイメージしてんじゃねえ！
もう少し…　もう少しだ！》
カカシ…。
クソッ　やられた！
せっかく苦労して
手に入れたものを！
リン…。
うお～っ！
《ここは　いったい　ここは何だ》
ヤツは何だ？
増援か？
バカが！　たった１人で！
《認めるか！》
《こんなもの！》
何だ　今のは！？
かわしたのか！？
《認めてやるもんか！》
血霧の里をなめるなよ！
《死ね！》
ぐあ～っ！
当たらない！？
何だ　アイツは！？
奇妙な術を使う！
せめて女だけでも回収しろ！
死体を絶対　敵に渡すな！
コイツ　間違いない！
すり抜けやがる！
（ゼツ）木遁　挿し木の術をいきなり！
オビト…　キミが　マダラに選ばれた
理由がわかったよ。
うお～っ！
何だ　アイツは？
そうか　俺は…。
俺は…　地獄にいる。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１２組の皆さんによる→